<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>InCoherentTerms</title>
        <description>Blog of Amin Zamani—Notes, stories, and experiments in writing out loud</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 12:17:31 +0200</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 12:17:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.4</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>My first video on YouTube</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I published my first YouTube video. It is a brief introduction to quantum computing in Persian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025-09-18/20250918-my-first-youtube-video.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot from my first video on YouTube&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I started doing it is mainly to practice presentation skills and to tell coherent stories based on the information I possess. I also imagine that this could lead to creating a community of people interested in the same topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first video took me more than 15 hours to prepare! It was mostly because I had many failed attempts. From the early stage of deciding what presentation platform to use (PowerPoint, Notion, web browser, or even writing live on iPad) to figuring out how to sew together short clips into a bigger one, each step needed a bit of experimentation. The hardest part for me, though, was convincing myself that a piece was good enough so that I could move on to making the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy about this event for a few reasons. Firstly, I have been thinking about publishing videos based on the things I know and I’m interested in for quite a while. To actually sit down and get it done from 0 to 100% is very different from just planning it in my head and imagining how it could or should look. Now it finally happened, and that imagination has taken form. The fact that it took a certain form brings me to my second reason. Now the &lt;em&gt;direction&lt;/em&gt; to continue further is a bit clearer. I wrote in an &lt;a href=&quot;/deciding-what-to-do-is-hard&quot;&gt;earlier post&lt;/a&gt; about how making decisions can be hard and how existing momentum in some direction can help make them easier. Before starting, I had all these routes in my mind about what kinds of things I could talk about. Now I have gained a certain momentum, and at least I know what I want to say and what makes sense to say in my second video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last reason I’m happy about this event is avoiding stagnation. Planning something, watching videos on how to do it, and imagining yourself doing it can be very pleasant and fulfilling. The problem is that this can go on for a while before you realize that nothing has actually happened. That’s why I think taking the first step forward by &lt;em&gt;making&lt;/em&gt; something is an important &lt;em&gt;milestone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that I keep on experimenting with this route and that it actually helps me feel a difference in the skills I seek to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/first-youtube-video</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/first-youtube-video</guid>
                
                <category>life notes</category>
                
                <category>reflections</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mental shotgun after watching BlackBerry</title>
                <description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025-09-08/20250908_black_berry.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;em&gt;BlackBerry&lt;/em&gt; (2023) yesterday. It is a movie based on what happened to BlackBerry, the cell phone manufacturing business. I tend to enjoy movies based on real stories. They can be both amusing and informative. I don’t know much about BlackBerry’s business other than what the movie presented. I recommend watching it to people who enjoy thinking about the working style and growth dynamics of technology startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t intend to comment on the cinematography of the movie. I spent a pleasant 2 hours watching it and that’s sufficient. It motivated me to refresh my memory of Paul Graham’s &lt;em&gt;Founder Mode&lt;/em&gt; essay. Graham writes “C-level execs, as a class, include some of the most skillful liars in the world” :) I remembered this when Jim Balsillie lied about liking Hockey at a lunch meeting with a potential acquirer to avoid disrupting the coherence of their momentary like-mindedness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another alarming scene for me was the deal that Jim Balsillie initially offered to Mike Lazaridis and Doug Fregin — 50% of the company and becoming its CEO in exchange of putting it on the right track. It is of course part of reality that the actual makers of the intellectual property are not always the ones who enjoy its potential financial value. This is especially the case in academic research groups. But it sometimes happens in industry settings as well. It’s similar to hydroelectric energy generation. The potential energy is right there behind the dam, but it needs a turbine to cash it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;images/2025-09-08/20250908_hydroelectric_energy.avif&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who enjoy working on the tech, the story is a reminder that investing in softer skills can be just as important for long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S.&lt;/em&gt; I borrowed the phrase &lt;em&gt;mental shotgun&lt;/em&gt; from Daniel Kahneman to refer to the many scattered thoughts that come to mind following a trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blackberry</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blackberry</guid>
                
                <category>writing practice</category>
                
                <category>storytelling</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Street painting</title>
                <description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025-08-31/20250831.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when walking in the streets of Munich, I see interesting teasers. This time, I saw a new modality of how to paint a picture!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/new-modality-of-painting</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/new-modality-of-painting</guid>
                
                <category>life notes</category>
                
                <category>storytelling</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Deciding what to do is hard</title>
                <description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025-08-30/20250830_deciding_what_to_do.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;Chatgpt&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the Netflix series &lt;em&gt;Dark&lt;/em&gt;, there’s a scene with an old man from the 19th century who has built an entire laboratory in his garage to create a time machine. What struck me wasn’t the machine itself, but where he got his motivation. His father had once told him about time travel, and he decided to devote his whole life to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is fiction, and I don’t take it literally. But it reminded me of a broader theme: deciding what to do with your life feels much harder today than it might have in those days. With the Internet and social media, we now know a lot about many people. We know what can be achieved within 5 or 10 years and that information increases our perceived opportunity cost of choosing any specific path. The more we know, the higher the bar gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn from Daniel Kahneman and others that decision making pulls from the same mental resources as solving math problems. It’s cognitively expensive. Even in a supermarket, debating whether to buy the chocolate bar by the cashier uses up energy. When it comes to more important things, like deciding what to focus on over the next 10 years of your life, which project to commit to, or how to sort out your values, it becomes even harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even starting this blog came with hesitation. If I write, it means I’m not doing something else: reading books, coding, diving into research papers, or less technical things like spending time with family. That’s the opportunity cost. And yet, there are things to gain: the pleasure of writing, the discipline of committing to a long-term personal project, and maybe a few insights along the way. The real struggle is figuring out how to weigh these trade-offs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst part of indecision is the stagnation it breeds. You can easily drift into doing nothing at all, simply because no option feels convincingly better than the rest. It becomes easier to convince yourself to do something when there are &lt;em&gt;external forces&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;boundary conditions&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;external force&lt;/em&gt; is the more obvious one—like when you have to do homework for school. By &lt;em&gt;boundary conditions&lt;/em&gt; I mean when you’ve already gained momentum in a specific direction. Then the choice feels less like a dilemma and more like a continuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-now&quot;&gt;What now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the point isn’t to find the perfect decision but to execute and iterate. Start doing something and accept that every choice comes with opportunity costs, and that’s okay. Once you start, you build up momentum and your inertia takes you forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/deciding-what-to-do-is-hard</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/deciding-what-to-do-is-hard</guid>
                
                <category>life notes</category>
                
                <category>reflections</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>When Logic Hurts</title>
                <description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025-08-24/20250824_logic_hurts_ChatGPT_Image.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;From wikipedia&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When talking with friends, I’ve noticed a certain bitterness in strictly logical, precise speech — it can sting and sometimes hurt feelings. I’ve always believed that being logical is a good thing: it makes discussions clearer, provides common ground for arguments, and ensures that everyone avoids confusion or misunderstanding. Yet, it doesn’t always work out for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep conversations strictly logical, you sometimes have to be a little harsh. You need to disagree often, to prevent people from slipping in faulty premises. If someone makes a statistical claim, you feel compelled to check whether they’re using the right reasoning. Everyday conversations are full of hindsight bias, sweeping generalizations, and conclusions drawn from tiny datasets. Even word choice becomes something to police: is it &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;em&gt;All men&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;some men&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;the average man&lt;/em&gt;? You get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a professional setting, this kind of rigor is valuable. But with friends, it often leaves people less happy than when the conversation started — and happiness is kind of the whole point of spending time together. Among friends, we expect to be heard, understood, accepted, and even allowed to make mistakes without feeling judged. Warmth and scrutiny rarely coexist easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People naturally get defensive when criticized. And it’s difficult to face too much criticism at once. Admitting you were wrong is a healthy practice, but it’s also extremely hard to do — maybe because it’s difficult to separate our &lt;em&gt;opinions&lt;/em&gt; from our &lt;em&gt;identity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-short&quot;&gt;In short&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logic is an incredible tool, but friendship isn’t a debate. Perhaps the real challenge is knowing when to prioritize accuracy and when to let warmth take the lead. After all, the goal with friends isn’t to win an argument — it’s to share time and leave each other feeling lighter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/logic</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/logic</guid>
                
                <category>life notes</category>
                
                <category>reflections</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>What is an accelerometer?</title>
                <description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025-08-24/20250824-Acelerometro_wikipedia.JPG&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; alt=&quot;From wikipedia&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Accelerometer from wikipedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An accelerometer is a device that measures linear acceleration. One of the simplest ways to build one is with a &lt;strong&gt;spring–mass system&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a car with a spring and a small test mass mounted inside. One end of the spring is fixed to the car’s body, and the other end is attached to the mass. If we orient the spring along the direction of the car’s motion, the system will respond whenever the car accelerates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
When the engine runs, the wheels push on the ground with a force $-F$, and the ground pushes back on the car with an equal and opposite force $F$. This force accelerates the entire car—including the spring–mass system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s the key: the fixed end of the spring accelerates exactly with the car, while the test mass resists the change in motion, as it is not connected to the car rigidly. The spring stretches or compresses, exerting a restoring force according to Hooke’s law. The displacement of the spring, $\Delta L$, becomes the observable to measure the car’s acceleration. The Hooke’s law applied here is&lt;/p&gt;

\[F - F&apos; = k \, \Delta L,\]

&lt;p&gt;where $k$ is the spring constant, $F$ the total force on the system, and $F’$ the force transmitted to the test mass. By calibrating $\Delta L$ against known accelerations $a$, we can turn spring displacement into a measurement of car’s acceleration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;accelerometers-in-free-fall&quot;&gt;Accelerometers in free fall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an interesting twist: a spring–mass accelerometer in free fall does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; measure Earth’s gravitational acceleration ($g = 9.8 \,\text{m/s^2}$). Instead, it reads &lt;strong&gt;zero&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Gravitational force on an object is proportional to its mass. The gravitational force is&lt;/p&gt;

\[F = G \frac{m M}{r^2},\]

&lt;p&gt;with $m$ the mass of the object, $M$ Earth’s mass, $r$ the distance to Earth’s center, and $G$ the gravitational constant. Because this force is proportional to $m$, the acceleration $a = F/m$ is the same for all mass elements of the system. In other words, every part of the spring and the test mass accelerate downward together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there’s no relative acceleration between the parts, the spring does not stretch or compress—it stays in its rest length. That’s why an accelerometer in free fall measures zero: it can only detect &lt;em&gt;proper acceleration&lt;/em&gt; (caused by forces other than gravity), not the pull of gravity itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-this-matters&quot;&gt;Why this matters?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An accelerometer is essentially a tiny spring–mass system that compares how much a test mass lags behind its support. It’s a beautiful example of how a simple physical principle underlies much of our modern technology, from navigation systems in phones to guidance in spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/accelerometer</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/accelerometer</guid>
                
                <category>physics</category>
                
                <category>navigation</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Graphic Designer On The Road</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A graphic designer is a professional within the graphic design and graphic arts industry who assembles together images, typography, or motion graphics to create a piece of design. A graphic designer creates the graphics primarily for published, printed or electronic media, such as brochures (sometimes) and advertising. They are also sometimes responsible for typesetting, illustration, user interfaces, web design, or take a teaching position. A core responsibility of the designer’s job is to present information in a way that is both accessible and memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A degree or certificate from an accredited trade school is usually considered essential for a graphic design position. After a career history has been established, though, the graphic designer’s experience and number of years in the business are considered the primary qualifications. A portfolio, which is the primary method for demonstrating these qualifications, is usually required to be shown at job interviews, and is constantly developed throughout a designer’s career. [&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphic_designer&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ice molecules can exhibit up to sixteen different phases &lt;em&gt;(packing geometries)&lt;/em&gt; that depend on temperature and pressure. When water is cooled rapidly (quenching), up to three different types of amorphous ice can form depending on the history of its pressure and temperature. When cooled slowly correlated proton tunneling occurs below 20 K giving rise to macroscopic quantum phenomena. Virtually all the ice on Earth’s surface and in its atmosphere is of a hexagonal crystalline structure denoted as ice Ih (spoken as “ice one h”) with minute traces of cubic ice denoted as ice Ic. The most common phase transition to ice Ih occurs when liquid water is cooled below 0°C (273.15K, 32°F) at standard atmospheric pressure. It may also be deposited directly by water vapor, as happens in the formation of frost. The transition from ice to water is melting and from ice directly to water vapor is sublimation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;characteristics&quot;&gt;Characteristics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a naturally-occurring crystalline inorganic solid with an ordered structure, ice is considered a mineral.[citation needed] It possesses a regular crystalline structure based on the molecule of water, which consists of a single oxygen atom covalently bonded to two hydrogen atoms, or H-O-H. However, many of the physical properties of water and ice are controlled by the formation of hydrogen bonds between adjacent oxygen and hydrogen atoms; while it is a weak bond, it is nonetheless critical in controlling the structure of both water and ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“ice contains no future , just the past, sealed away. As if they’re alive, everything in the world is sealed up inside, clear and distinct. Ice can preserve all kinds of things that way- cleanly, clearly. That’s the essence of ice, the role it plays.”
&lt;cite&gt;― Haruki Murakami&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An unusual property of ice frozen at atmospheric pressure is that the solid is approximately 8.3% less dense than liquid water. The density of ice is 0.9167 g/cm3 at 0 °C,[4] whereas water has a density of 0.9998 g/cm³ at the same temperature. Liquid water is densest, essentially 1.00 g/cm³, at 4 °C and becomes less dense as the water molecules begin to form the hexagonal crystals[5] of ice as the freezing point is reached. This is due to hydrogen bonding dominating the intermolecular forces, which results in a packing of molecules less compact in the solid. Density of ice increases slightly with decreasing temperature and has a value of 0.9340 g/cm³ at −180 °C (93 K).[6]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When water freezes, it increases in volume (about 9% for freshwater).[7] The effect of expansion during freezing can be dramatic, and ice expansion is a basic cause of freeze-thaw weathering of rock in nature and damage to building foundations and roadways from frost heaving. It is also a common cause of the flooding of houses when water pipes burst due to the pressure of expanding water when it freezes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of this process is that ice &lt;em&gt;(in its most common form)&lt;/em&gt; floats on liquid water, which is an important feature in Earth’s biosphere. It has been argued that without this property, natural bodies of water would freeze, in some cases permanently, from the bottom up,[8] resulting in a loss of bottom-dependent animal and plant life in fresh and sea water. Sufficiently thin ice sheets allow light to pass through while protecting the underside from short-term weather extremes such as wind chill. This creates a sheltered environment for bacterial and algal colonies. When sea water freezes, the ice is riddled with brine-filled channels which sustain sympagic organisms such as bacteria, algae, copepods and annelids, which in turn provide food for animals such as krill and specialised fish like the bald notothen, fed upon in turn by larger animals such as emperor penguins and minke whales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When ice melts, it absorbs as much energy as it would take to heat an equivalent mass of water by 80 °C. During the melting process, the temperature remains constant at 0 °C. While melting, any energy added breaks the hydrogen bonds between ice (water) molecules. Energy becomes available to increase the thermal energy (temperature) only after enough hydrogen bonds are broken that the ice can be considered liquid water. The amount of energy consumed in breaking hydrogen bonds in the transition from ice to water is known as the heat of fusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with water, ice absorbs light at the red end of the spectrum preferentially as the result of an overtone of an oxygen-hydrogen (O-H) bond stretch. Compared with water, this absorption is shifted toward slightly lower energies. Thus, ice appears blue, with a slightly greener tint than for liquid water. Since absorption is cumulative, the color effect intensifies with increasing thickness or if internal reflections cause the light to take a longer path through the ice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/Graphic-Designer-On-The-Road</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Graphic-Designer-On-The-Road</guid>
                
                <category>Template</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;Tom&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &apos;Hi, Tom&apos; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll</guid>
                
                <category>Template</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Review: A Week With the Apple Watch</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Apple Watch&lt;/strong&gt; is a smartwatch developed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple Inc&lt;/a&gt;. It incorporates fitness tracking and health-oriented capabilities as well as integration with iOS and other Apple products and services. The device is available in four variants: Apple Watch Sport, Apple Watch, Apple Watch Hermès, and Apple Watch Edition. The Watch is distinguished by different combinations of cases and first or third party interchangeable bands. Apple Watch relies on a wirelessly connected iPhone to perform many of its default functions such as calling and texting. It is compatible with the iPhone 5 or later models running iOS 8.2 or later, through the use of Bluetooth or Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announced by Tim Cook on September 9, 2014, the device was available for pre-order on April 10 and began shipping on April 24, 2015. The Apple Watch quickly became the best-selling wearable device, with the shipment of 4.2 million smartwatches in the second quarter of 2015, according to analyst firm Canalys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You can only do so many things great, and you should cast aside everything else.”
&lt;cite&gt;― Tim Cook&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumors surrounded an Apple-developed wearable back as far as 2011, which conceptualized the device as a variation of the iPod that would curve around the user’s wrist, and feature Siri integration. On February 10, 2013, both The New York Times and The Wall Street Journal reported that Apple was beginning to develop an iOS-based smartwatch with a curved display. On February 12, 2013, Bloomberg reported that Apple’s smartwatch project was “beyond the experimentation phase in its development”, and had a team of at least 100 designers were working on the project. Further reports in March 2013 indicated that Apple planned to release the device by the end of the year. In July 2013, Financial Times reported that Apple had begun hiring more employees to work on the smartwatch, and that it was targeting a possible retail release in late 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unveiling--release&quot;&gt;Unveiling &amp;amp; Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2014, Apple CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tim_Cook&quot;&gt;Tim Cook&lt;/a&gt; told The Wall Street Journal that the company was planning to launch new product categories that year, but did not reveal any specifics. In June 2014, Reuters reported that production was expected to begin in July for a release in October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple Watch was first unveiled after a classic and ever infamous &lt;em&gt;“We do have ‘one more thing’…”&lt;/em&gt; slide, which heard enormous applause, on September 9, 2014 during a press event which also saw the introduction of the iPhone 6. After the reveal video, the auditorium erupted with applause while Tim Cook rolled back his sleeve, revealing an Apple Watch on his wrist. Speaking about the device, Apple CEO Tim Cook explained that Apple Watch was “a new, intimate way to communicate from your wrist, and a comprehensive health and fitness device.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison to other Apple products and competing smartwatches, marketing of Apple Watch focused more on advertising the device as a fashion accessory; a 12-page advertising spread for Apple Watch in an issue of Vogue focused primarily on the different body and band styles available, and downplayed the technological aspects of it. Apple has also, in particular, focused upon its health and fitness-oriented features, competing against dedicated activity trackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-card width-full caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/apple-watch-in-car.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple Watch&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Apple watch on the wrist&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;release&quot;&gt;Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-orders for Apple Watch began on April 10, 2015, with an official release on April 24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On launch, Apple Watch was not available at Apple Store; beginning on April 10, 2015, customers could receive appointments for demonstrations and fitting, but the device was not in-stock for walk-in purchase, and had to be reserved and ordered online (however, sales representatives are able to assist in the process). CNET felt that this distribution model was designed to prevent Apple Store locations from having long line-ups due to high demand. Selected Apple Watch models were available in-store at certain luxury boutiques and authorized Apple resellers in limited quantities. On June 4, 2015, Apple announced that it did plan to stock Apple Watch models at its retail locations. On August 24, 2015 during an earnings call, Best Buy announced that it would begin stocking Apple Watch at its retail stores by the end of September. Both T-Mobile US and Sprint also announced plans to offer Apple Watch through its retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Design is a funny word. Some people think design means how it looks. But of course, if you dig deeper, it’s really how it works.” &lt;cite&gt;― Steve Jobs&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On September 9, 2015, in Apple’s Special Event, Apple launched a new collection of Apple Watch in a collaboration with Hermès. This new collection of Apple Watch is named as Apple Watch Hermès, comes in stainless steel body with finely crafted leather bands in distinctive styles from Hermès, including the Single Tour, Double Tour and Cuff models. Apple Watch Hermès is available only in selected retail stores of Apple and Hermès.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The device was not branded as “iWatch” (which would put it in line with its other product lines) due to trademark conflicts in certain territories; in the United States, the iWatch trademark is owned by OMG Electronics—who was crowdfunding a device under the same name, and is owned in the European Union by Irish firm Probendi. In July 2015, Probendi sued Apple Inc. for trademark infringement, arguing that through keyword advertising on the Google search engine, it caused advertising for the Apple Watch to appear on search results pages when users searched for the trademarked term “iWatch”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple Watch finally goes on sale in India on Nov. 6. The device also has launched in Chile, the Philippines, and South Africa.  [ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Watch&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/a-week-with-the-apple-watch</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-week-with-the-apple-watch</guid>
                
                <category>Template</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Basic Rules For Walking In The Mountains</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;United States, Canada, the Republic of Ireland, and United Kingdom,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;hiking&lt;/strong&gt; refers to walking outdoors on a trail, or off trail, for recreational purposes. A day hike refers to a hike that can be completed in a single day. However, in the United Kingdom, the word walking is also used, as well as rambling, while walking in mountainous areas is called hillwalking. In Northern England, Including the Lake District and Yorkshire Dales, fellwalking describes hill or mountain walks, as fell is the common word for both features there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiking can sometimes involves bushwhacking and hiking is sometimes referred to as such. This specifically refers to difficult walking through dense forest, undergrowth, or bushes, where forward progress requires pushing vegetation aside. In extreme cases of bushwhacking, where the vegetation is so dense that human passage is impeded, a machete is used to clear a pathway. The Australian term bushwalking refers to both on and off-trail hiking. Common terms for hiking used by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Zealand&quot;&gt;New Zealanders&lt;/a&gt; are tramping (particularly for overnight and longer trips), walking or bushwalking. Trekking is the preferred word used to describe multi-day hiking in the mountainous regions of India, Pakistan, Nepal, North America, South America, Iran and in the highlands of East Africa. Hiking a long-distance trail from end-to-end is also referred to as trekking and as thru-hiking in some places. In North America, multi-day hikes, usually with camping, are referred to as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Backpacking_(wilderness)&quot;&gt;backpacking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;long-distance-hiking&quot;&gt;Long Distance Hiking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frequently nowadays long distance hikes (walking tours) are undertaken along long distance paths, including the National Trails in England and Wales, the National Trail System in the USA and The Grande Randonnée (France), Grote Routepaden, or Lange-afstand-wandelpaden (Holland), Grande Rota (Portugal), Gran Recorrido (Spain) is a network of long-distance footpaths in Europe, mostly in France, Belgium, the Netherlands and Spain. There are extensive networks in other European countries of long distance trails, as well as in Canada, Australia, New Zealand, Nepal, and to a lesser extent other Asiatic countries, like Turkey, Israel, and Jordan. In the Alps of Austria, Slovenia, Switzerland, Germany, France, and Italy walking tours are often made from ‘hut-to-hut’, using an extensive system of mountain huts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-card width-full caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/mountain-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mountain&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Norway is Beautiful&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 20th-century there has been a proliferation of official and unofficial long distance routes, which mean that hikers now are more likely to refer to using a long distance way (Britain), trail (USA), The Grande Randonnée (France), etc., than setting out on a walking tour. Early examples of long distance paths, include the Appalachian Trail in the USA and the Pennine Way in Britain. Pilgrimage routes are now treated, by some walkers, as long distance routes, and the route taken by the British National Trail the North Downs Way closely follows that of the Pilgrims’ Way to Canterbury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hiking times can be estimated by Naismith’s rule or Tobler’s hiking function.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;equipment&quot;&gt;Equipment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The equipment required for hiking depends on the length of the hike, but day hikers generally carry at least water, food, a map, and rain-proof gear. Hikers usually wear sturdy hiking boots for mountain walking and backpacking, as protection from the rough terrain, as well as providing increased stability. The Mountaineers club recommends a list of “Ten Essentials” equipment for hiking, including a compass, sunglasses, sunscreen, a flashlight, a first aid kit, a fire starter, and a knife. Other groups recommend items such as hat, gloves, insect repellent, and an emergency blanket. A GPS navigation device can also be helpful and route cards may be used as a guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Returning home is the most difficult part of long-distance hiking; You have grown outside the puzzle and your piece no longer fits.”
&lt;cite&gt;― Cindy Ross&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proponents of ultralight backpacking argue that long lists of required items for multi-day hikes increases pack weight, and hence fatigue and the chance of injury. Instead, they recommend reducing pack weight, in order to make hiking long distances easier. Even the use of hiking boots on long-distances hikes is controversial among ultralight hikers, because of their weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;environmental-impact&quot;&gt;Environmental Impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural environments are often fragile, and may be accidentally damaged, especially when a large number of hikers are involved. For example, years of gathering wood can strip an alpine area of valuable nutrients. and some species, such as martens or bighorn sheep, are very sensitive to the presence of humans, especially around mating season. Generally, protected areas such as parks have regulations in place to protect the environment, so as to minimize such impact. Such regulations include banning wood fires, restricting camping to established camp sites, disposing or packing out faecal matter, and imposing a quota on the number of hikers. Many hikers espouse the philosophy of Leave No Trace, following strict practices on dealing with food waste, food packaging, and other impact on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human waste is often a major source of environmental impact from hiking, and can contaminate the watershed and make other hikers ill. ‘Catholes’ dug 10 to 25 cm (4 to 10 inches) deep, depending on local soil composition and covered after use, at least 60 m (200 feet) away from water sources and trails, are recommended to reduce the risk of bacterial contamination. [ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hiking&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/basic-rules-for-walking-in-the-mountains</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/basic-rules-for-walking-in-the-mountains</guid>
                
                <category>Template</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>